<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arne Rossmann</title><link>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Arne Rossmann</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shaking the Kinder egg - or: metadata of Data Products?</title><link>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/post/2022-02-09_metadata-dataproduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/post/2022-02-09_metadata-dataproduct/</guid><description>Shaking the Kinder egg - or: metadata of Data Products Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t done it? shaking the Kinder eggs to &amp;ldquo;guess&amp;rdquo; what&amp;rsquo;s inside and raise the chance of getting one of the figures. We even put them on the vegetable scale to increase the chance (many many years back the figures had higher weight than the assemble stuff). But in the end, it was all guessing.
When we deal with data, we don&amp;rsquo;t want to guess.</description></item><item><title>Presentations</title><link>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/presentations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/presentations/</guid><description>Presentations DevOps in a Nutshell : A short an highlevel introduction into DevOps Business Data Lake Best Practices : Why the Business Data Lake works and which Services the Business Data Lake should provide. Organizations can use the Business Data Lake concept best when they standardize, industrialize and innovate. Modern Data Platforms : To be able to use analytics effectively and thus leverage the data treasures in the company, you need a modern and scalable data platform that can react flexibly to events and was designed with a DataOps mindset from the very beginning.</description></item><item><title>Data Mesh - not such a new concept after all?</title><link>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/post/2022-01-28_datamesh-not-so-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/post/2022-01-28_datamesh-not-so-new/</guid><description>Not such a new concept after all? I don&amp;rsquo;t think that I have to tell much about the recent developments on Data Mesh (see this and that), the world doesn&amp;rsquo;t need another &amp;ldquo;Data Mesh introduction&amp;rdquo; article just to tell these things again.
But when we dig deeper into that topic and look on the Data Product there might be some similarities ringing a bell. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to this later.
But how is a Data Product defined (by Zhamak)?</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/about/</guid><description>About me I&amp;rsquo;m an enthuist Enterprise Architect for Big Data, Cloud, Analytics and the related topics. I love to learn new technologies and methods and play around with them. Apart from the technical perspective I&amp;rsquo;m interested in agile methodologies, coaching teams on their journey towards agile and DevOps.
Current research topics Currently I&amp;rsquo;m researching and experimenting with KnowledgeGraphs and GraphQL.
Technologies</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/post/2021-11-24_first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/post/2021-11-24_first-post/</guid><description>Hello World package main import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; func main() { fmt.Println(&amp;#34;hello world&amp;#34;) }</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/imprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataworldliving.fly.dev/imprint/</guid><description>Legal Disclosure Information in accordance with the applicable law
Arne Rossmann
Disclaimer All thoughts in posts on this page are on my own.
Theme Anatole</description></item></channel></rss>